experiencelife.com 2016-06-10

# Privacy Policy · Experience Life

Welcome to Experience Life. Your privacy is important to us. Please take a moment to carefully review our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. Our Organization and Web Site Experience Life Magazine is published monthly except for January/February and July/August by Life Time Fitness, a healthy lifestyle brand consisting of health and fitness centers, healthy… [Read more »](https://experiencelife.com/privacy-policy/ "ReadPrivacy Policy")

Welcome to _Experience Life_. Your privacy is important to us. Please take a moment to carefully review our Privacy Policy and [Terms of Service](http://experiencelife.com/terms-of-service).

## Our Organization and Web Site

_Experience Life_ Magazine is published monthly except for January/February and July/August by Life Time Fitness, a healthy lifestyle brand consisting of health and fitness centers, healthy living products, and educational services.

The information contained in the magazine is intended to provide broad understanding and knowledge of healthcare topics. This information should not be considered complete and should not be used in place of a visit, call, consultation or advice from your physician or other healthcare provider. We recommend you consult your physician or healthcare professional before beginning or altering your personal exercise, diet or supplementation program.

Life Time Fitness Corporate Headquarters  
2902 Corporate Place  
Chanhassen, MN 55317

_Experience Life_ Magazine  
2145 Ford Parkway, Suite 302  
St. Paul, MN 55116

This privacy policy covers [www.experiencelife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/), [www.experiencelifemag.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/), [elmag.com](http://elmag.com/), [revolutionaryact.com](http://www.revolutionaryact.com/ "Revolutionary Act") and the “[101 Revolutionary Ways to Be Healthy](http://experiencelife.com/app/ "“101 Revolutionary Ways to Be Healthy” App")” mobile application (for iPhone, iPad, Kindle Fire and Android devices). By visiting our site, you agree that your visit and any dispute over privacy are governed by this Privacy Policy, as well as our [Terms of Service](http://experiencelife.com/terms-of-service).

## Anonymous Access

You can access our Web site homepage and browse our site without disclosing your personal data.

## Services and Links

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) allows users to communicate with other visitors or to post information to be accessed by others in our blogs, forums and comment sections.

Our Web site does include links to third party Web service providers, as well as other sites. [ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of other Web sites.

We may contract with other companies to perform services on our behalf. We may need to provide only such personally identifiable information about you as necessary for such purposes.

## Automatic Collection of Information

We do not automatically log personal data nor do we link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals. We do use “cookies” to store personal data, but we do not link non-personal information in cookies with personal data about specific individuals.

## Data Collection and Purpose Specification

We collect personal data that is expressly volunteered by the visitor while using our services. This information is used to notify users of updates and opportunities (special offers and giveaways, for instance) at our site, and to improve the content selection of [ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/).

We do not collect information about our visitors from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organizations.

Information collected may be shared in the aggregate with others and may be used for our own business purposes. It is never shared for commercial purposes.

## Children’s Policy

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) is not intended for use by minors, especially children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal data nor solicit in any manners to persons under 13 years of age.

Children are not permitted to provide personal information, buy subscriptions, or use our public areas (blogs, forums, article comment boards) without parental permission.

## Confidentiality/Security

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) maintains a secure order form for subscribing to _Experience Life_ Magazine, which requires personal and financial information from you should you choose to subscribe online (name, billing information, shipping address, e-mail, credit card information, expiration date).

Upon submitting your subscription order, we will disclose your name, address and transaction information to our subscription fulfillment center in order to process your purchase. To complete the transaction, we will disclose your credit card information to the appropriate bank or credit card company.

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect your personal data that we have under our control from:

  *  Unauthorized access
  * Improper use and disclosure
  * Unauthorized modification
  * Unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors’ personal data.

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.

## Registration

Registration is not required for using this site. Should you choose to register for a blog or forum, for instance, certain contact information must be provided (for instance, your email address); we will not sell this information.

## E-newsletters

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) publishes 12 monthly newsletters and 52 weekly newsletters annually, along with occasional special promotion emails (no more than one per month). In order to subscribe, you must provide your email address; we will not share this with other organizations.

All e-newsletters sent by _Experience Life_ are in compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, and contain an opt-out option, the postal address for Life Time Fitness, and accurate and explanative subject lines and headers. Users may cancel their subscription to our e-newsletter at any time by sending us as email or by using the opt-out option.

## Security

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) has taken security measures to protect users against loss, misuse and modification of personal information that is maintained within our site. No data communication over the Internet is completely secure, however. When sharing personal information, you do so at your own risk; we cannot guarantee the security of the information provided, but we will do our very best to protect your information.

## Postings and Privacy

The information you post in any comment board, forum or blog at our site is available to anyone with Internet access. Submit information at your own risk and please take the necessary precautions to protect yourself. For more information on the content posted by other users on our site, please see our [Terms of Service](http://experiencelife.com/terms-of-service). For more information on commenting specifically, please see our [Comment Policy](http://experiencelife.com/comment-policy/ "Comment Policy").

## Accessing Your Personal Data

You can find out whether we are keeping personal data about you by emailing us at [experiencelife@experiencelife.com](mailto:experiencelife@experiencelife.com). Upon request, we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data we have within a month, free of charge.

We do reserve the right to require proof of your identity before providing the information.

We allow you to challenge the information we hold about you and, where appropriate, you may have the data rectified or amended.

We do not reserve the right to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal data.

## Policy Changes

[ExperienceLife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/) reserves the right to change any or all of the Privacy Policy at any time without notice or liability to users. Additions or changes to this policy will be posted here, and the most recent version will always be available at [www.experiencelife.com](http://www.experiencelife.com/). Changes to this policy will be considered accepted by you upon continued use of the site.

This policy was last updated on November 12, 2012.

If you have an inquiry or concern about this policy, please contact [jmartin@experiencelife.com](mailto:jkuenster@experiencelife.com?subject=ExperienceLife.com%20Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry/Concern).
